he made this kind of
он там э сделал вот такой как бы тезис
thesis that the negation of everything that exists, that
тся что отрицание всего сущего что у
every uh existing thing in this world has some kind of
каждого ээ сущего в этом мире есть некая
opposite substance that
противоположная субстанция которая его
complements it and replaces it
дополняет и взаимо заменяет
very much. I too, I also
вот очень Я тоже я тоже много времени
thought about this a lot of time, I know this thesis, I thought
над этим думал я знаю эту тезу я думал
about it  this That is, how would it be interesting
над этим То есть как бы это ну интересно
at least
как минимум
Hello, are you a
Здравствуйте Вы
philosopher, what is your opinion on the dualistic
философ как относитесь к дуалистической
theory of
теории
Socrates, dualism not only
Сократа дуализм не только
sucks because Lenin later developed these
сосу том что Ленин потом развил эти
dualistic
дуалистические
theories of the kind, this begins with
теории роде это начина
the fact that Socrates said that there is some kind
тому что Сократ говорил что есть некая
of substance that gives rise to everything that
такая субстанция которая порождает всё
exists Yes, I  I myself have been thinking about this for many years
сущее Да я и сам не один год над этим
and even now I’m thinking about it, that is, but
думал и даже сейчас о думаю то есть но
these are too deep topics. That is,
это слишком глубинные темы То есть как
well, yes, there is such a thing, I’m thinking about it and what do
бы ну да есть такое дело думаю об этом а
you think about it?
вы как об этом
I’m more
думаете я более
inclined towards the teachings of Plato. The thing is,
Платона склоняюсь Дело в том что вот
remember when  he introduced the concept of
помните когда он ээ ввёл понятие
ether ether Yes, and he said that Ether is uh the
эфира эфира Да и сказал что Эфир есть ээ
creation of the world, if you remember Plato
создание миро вот если вы помните Платон
wrote metaphysics wrote wrote yes, and it was
метафизику написал писал писал да вот и
precisely in this work that he introduced the
как раз вот именно он в этом труде ввёл
concept of ether, which until the 15th century
понятие эфира которое до XV века ещё
was still present in various scientific and
присутствовало в разных научных и
philosophical treatises  then
философских трактатах потом от него
they abandoned it Yes, but now there are a lot of
отказались Да но сейчас очень много
philosophers. For example, the French
философов Вот например французский
George de Bois, he returns to the
Джордж де буа он возвращается к
concept of Plato’s ether
концепции платоновского эфира
and wants to give it a new breath in that
и хочет ему дать новое дыхание в том что
I graduated from the Faculty of Philosophy of the
я заканчивал философский факультет
Kiev National
Киевского национального университета
Shevchenko University, I have 18 years of practice Yes,
имени Шевченко у меня 18 лет практики Да
in 2 years it will be
через 2 года будет
I’m working on the twentieth, I’m a researcher, and maybe
двадцатом занимаюсь я есть научный
quite stupidly. That is, as it
порядочно бестолково быть может То есть
were, and that’s why I can’t get away with this,
как бы и поэтому тут этим кануть не могу
but in general, I’m interested in the philosophy of the ancient Greeks
но в целом меня философия древних греков
when Although I think it’s extremely important,
когда Хотя я считаю она крайне важна но
I’m more interested in the philosophy of Europe in the
меня больше интересует философия Европы
1900s, that is, what exactly are your theses
X X X век то есть какие именно тезисы вы
This era
этой эпохи
is highlighted by my favorite philosopher -
выделяет мой любимый философ -
this is Arthur
это Артур
Sangar and his my favorite thesis life is
Сангар и его мой любимый тезис жизнь -
something that in theory should not be this is
это то чего не должно по идее быть это
number one number two but in general his
номер один номер два но в целом его
thesis I did not call for suicide
тезис Я не призывал к самоубийству
Let's just live somehow Smart so that
Давайте просто жить как-то Умно чтобы ну
you  We understand that Schopenhauer still has a very
вы поняли у шопенгауэра ещё есть очень
kind of work
вы какую работу
I advise you to read he has about the
я вам советую почитать у него есть о
nature of things called I read I read
природе вещей называется Я читал Я читал
the calculations some excerpts Yes, and
выкладки кое-какие отрывки Да вот и он
he did there, like a thesis like
он там сделал вот такой как бы тезис
that the negation of all things that
нравится что отрицание всего сущего что
every thing has  in this world there is a certain
каждого сущего в этом мире есть некая
opposite substance that
противоположная субстанция которая его
complements it and replaces each other
дополняет и взаимо
also a lot of time on um I know
заменяет тоже много времени на эм Я знаю
this thesis I thought about it That is, how would it be
эту тезу я думал над этим То есть как бы
interesting at least, that is, yes,
это ну интересно как минимум то есть да
and you finished that Oh I
а вы заканчивали что О я за закончил
graduated from technical education  something that is Well,
закончил технический вз о чём то есть Ну
also Under the Soviet Union Yes, well, absolutely
ещё При Советском Союзе Да ну безусловно
Yes, well, that is, dialectical materialism
Да ну то есть диалектический материализм
anyway, it turns out Well, of
всё равно вы изучали получается Ну
course yes yes Oh well, that is, basic not not not not
конечно да да О ну то есть базовые не не
No not dialectical And
не не Нет не диалектический А
materialistic well, dialectical
материалистические ну диалектический
materialism is called well God
материализм это называется ну Бог с ним
bless him  so I won’t argue, and Well, again,
Пусть так Спорить не буду и Ну опять же
since I was a
поскольку я был
technician, I was little more
технаря это мало меня больше
interested in the theoretical basis of
интересовала теоретически основа
electrical engineering. That is, it’s
электротехники То есть как бы на самом
actually logical, yes. And everything that we have just
деле логично да А всё то что мы сейчас с
talked to you for these 5 minutes is a hobby
вами говорили эти 5 минут это хобби
because yes, when you were young  Yes,
потому что да Когда вы были молодой да
you would be more interested in having this
вам больше бы интересовало чтобы вас эта
electric machine run with electric current, and the shorter it is to
машина электрич нело током да чем короче
understand Plato, on the contrary, when I
разбираться в Платона наоборот когда я
was young, I was the same as when I was
был молодой меня так же как когда и
old. I was interested in this
старый Меня интересовало чтобы это
electric machine working because
электричес машина работала пото что
because they pay me money for it, too,
потому что мне за это платят деньги тоже
right. And now  already for the soul, the
правильно А сейчас уже для души чем
more we get older, the more
больше к преклонном возрасту Тем больше
we begin to think about the philosophical
мы начинаем задумываться о философской
structure of the universe no no no you are wrong
структуре мироздания нене не Вы не правы
on the contrary
наоборот
uh I realized in my first year that I
ээ Я ещё на первом курсе осознал что я
had gone to the wrong place, that techies are through
пошёл не туда что технари - это через
force and my soul lies in the
силу а душа лежит у меня гуманитарным
humanities but already  it was Poznyak Mitai and
наукам но уже было позняк митаи и
that’s why I stayed technically, that is, but because
поэтому я остался техён то есть но из-за
I realized that I had made a serious
того что я понял что совершил жёсткую
mistake.
ошибку
I read both Kant and not and other
Я читал и Канта и ни и прочих прочих
other others. Uh-huh. And what do you
прочих Угу А что вы
think, say,
типа скажем вот думаете
about Schopenhauer’s thesis about
по тезисом шопенгауэра о
the opposition of racial theory? That
противопоставлении расовой теории То
is, he  because they had already begun
есть он потому что уже начали
to emerge in Europe, then Hitler developed it,
зарождаться в Европе потом Гитлер развил
of course, and in Europe then the
конечно да в Европе тогда уже начали
ideas of the concept of preventing peoples from mixing had already begun to emerge.
идеи понятия чтобы народы не смешивались
And Ngau was just in favor of
А нгау как раз выступал за
this and the thesis of one person 20 Nations he
так и тезис один человек 20 Наций у него
had, he
было у него вот есть
still has work, but it’s in Russian  the language is not
ещё работа но она на русский язык не
translated there it is called a
переведена есть вот она называется
man of Nations what is there The fact is that at
человек д Наций что там Дело в том что в
that time in Europe there were
то время в Европе было больших Наций
about 20 large Nations and he believed that when there was a
порядка 20 и он считал что когда будет
mixture of different peoples there would be a single
смешение разных народов так будет единое
European State and a single
Европейское Государство и единая
European nation
европейская нация
so deeply I did
так глубоко Я
n’t know the shang  I exploded my young
шанга не познал я взрыв моём молодом
brain about
мозгу примерно года
20 years old when I read his book, I don’t remember
20т когда я прочитал его книгу не помню
which one But this is his main treatise that
какая Но это главный его трактат что
human life is something that
человеческая жизнь - это то чего не
should not exist for me it was so simple there
должно быть мне это настолько просто
was confusion in some soul and I read
смятение было в какой-то душе и я читал
his 20 pages there  he compares
там его страниц 20 вот он сравнивает
insects Why do they live?
насекомых Почему живут снит Почему дию
and medals
ветеранам дают кресты ордена и медали
instead of just giving them money so
вместо того чтобы просто дать им денег
that they can be treated and rest where they
чтобы они лечились и отдыхали там где
want, but in fact the answer is simple
хотят а на самом деле ответ-то простой
in terms of shanga and there’s just no money, there’s just
по шанга а просто денег нет просто денег
no money because it’s much cheaper to stamp medals
нет потому что на штамповать медали это
than to give everyone
гораздо дешевле чем каждому дать там
some portion there  money for him to
какую-то порцию денег чтобы он сам
go to any resorts he wants, and so
поехал на какие угодно курорты и так
on, then then I do
далее потом потом я помню
n’t remember the pong about nations, I remember that
понга про нации не помню я помню что
life is something that shouldn’t happen, I thought
жизнь это то чего не должно быть я думал
that he was pessimistic, it seemed to me that at the end of
что он пессимизм Мне казалось что концу
the book, besides, let’s open a vein,
книги прит к тому что давайте вскроем ве
but no  He lived a long life he said
но нет Он прожил долгую жизнь он сказал
at the
в
end You should not take my work
конце Вы не должны воспринимать мой труд
as pessimism Because I did not call
как пессимизм Потому что я не призывал
anyone to commit suicide and thanks to my
никого к самоубийству и благодаря своей
philosophy monini this
философии монини это
and Thanks to my philosophy I lived
и Благодаря моей философии я прожил
such a long life that is all that
такую долгую жизнь то есть вот и всё что
I remember from the ping I understood  uh, Shopin Gaur
я помню из пинга понял э у Шопин гаура
also had this denial
ещё было Э вот это отрицание
of the material,
материального
uh, that’s when he wrote about something like,
ээ вот когда он про писал вот типа что
uh, there’s a lot of everyone, but there’s not enough of everything. He
ээ всех много а всего мало Вот у него
has this thesis, which means everyone wants everything, but there’s a
есть такая тези значит все хотят всё но
lot of everyone, and there’s not enough of everything. I really
всех много а всего мало вот мне очень
like this phrase of his.  that is, Why
нравится его эта фраза да то есть Почему
You came so right Yes, why do they
Вот вы так правильно пришли Да почему
give medals because there is
Типа дают медали потому что денег на
not enough money for everyone, if so Putin takes the
всех не хватает если так Путин забирает
money for himself Putin and the oligarchs, and then of
деньги себе Путин и олигархи да то
course from Wagner or someone
конечно из Вагнера или кого-то мобили
who was sent to Ukraine they will give him
который послали в Украину ему дадут
a medal they will give him a medal Because  that
медальку ему дадут медальку Потому что
there is no money Because the money was spent on a yacht
денег нет Потому что деньги ушли на яхту
Yes, for example, on some kind of drugs for
Да например на какие-то наркотики на
girls and so on Yes, that’s a
девочек и так дальше Да вот
shanga, by the way, modern Russia, it
и шанга кстати современная Россия она
reflects
отображает
Schopenhauer’s one, he thought
вот у шопенгауэра есть такая он
about the nature of the state Yes, and
размышлял о природе государства Да и у
he had an ideal state Yes, he did
него было идеальное государство Да он
called Atlantis That's just in the
его назвал Атлантида Вот по как раз на
ancient Greek manner Yes, and
древнегреческий манер Да и
uh, the second state is like the antipode of
э второе государство как антипод
Atlantis Yes, he called the pande pande, so
Атлантиды Да он назвал панде панде вот
he had a pande in such
панде у него значит было на таких
volcanic territories there, in short, there were
вулканических территориях там короче
always some kind of cataclysms constantly
постоянно какие-то катаклизмы постоянно
on the tin and the rulers of the pandeans they always
на жесть и правители пандей они всегда
took into themselves  all the money from all the
забирали в себе все деньги из всех
resources of the panda, it was in, uh, in a zone of
ресурсов панде она была в ээ в зоне
seismic activity, a lot of mines
сейсмической активности очень много шахт
were very rich because they mined
было очень богатая потому что добывали
a lot of ore But people lived poorly And
очень много руды Но люди жили бедно И
so I see that modern Russia it
вот я смотрю что современная Россия она
somehow reflects Here are the sword
как-то отображает Вот шпага ские
views on the panda volcanic
воззрения на панде вулканическое
activity  mountains That is, you have
активность гор То есть у вас есть и
Kamchatka, and the Caucasus mountains and a bunch of everything,
Камчатка Да и горы Кавказ и куча всего
and huge
да огромный
deposits of all kinds of ore, gold, gas, oil,
залежи всякой руды золота газа нефти
diamonds, the rulers, like in this panda,
алмазов правители как в этой панде
take everything for themselves, and the common people
забирают всё себе а простой народ он
live in poverty and destitution, and the modern
живёт бедно и нищем да и а современный
world, for example, is developed there
мир например как вот развитый там
Great Britain USA they turn out like
Великобритания США они получаются как
Atlantis, where
Атлантида там более равномерно
material wealth is more evenly distributed and people
распределяются материальные блага и люди
live in abundance You don’t find it No, I do
живут в достатке Вот вы не находите это
n’t find it What exactly is wrong, what doesn’t
Нет не нахожу А что именно не так что не
coincide with ros Well first of all,
совпадает с ро с Ну вопервых
one of the greatest philosophers
нга один из величайших философов
of the Renaissance That is, it’s possible
Ренессанса То есть как бы ну можно
to say with some stretch our
сказать с некоторой натяжкой наш
Contemporary and he extended his Thesis
Современник и он свои Тез распространял
to all 204 countries including and the first was
на все 204 страны включая а первая была
Germany in the abstract he thought about the
Германия абстрактно он размышлял о
nature of the best state
природе наилучшего госуда
there existed no then look then there
там существовали нет тогда смотри тогда
was not a single country that fell
ни одной страны не было которая попадала
into his ideal and therefore he described yes about
в его идеал и поэтому он описал да о
nature  uh reign Yes,
природе ээ правление Да
uh, the ideal country of Atlantis Yes, and
ээ идеальную страну Атлантиду Да и
the antipode of its panda Yes, I see that according to
антипод её панде Да вот я смотрю что по
his description, modern ones, for example
его описанию современные например
Britain, the modern USA, they are still far
Британия современные США они ещё далеки
from Atlantis, but are already approaching it
до Атлантиды но уже приближаются к ней
in terms of relationships between people in terms of
по взаимоотношения между людьми по
living standards, and Russia is exactly how it
уровню жизни а Россия она вот прямо как
already defines  panda The only thing about the
уже определяет панде Единственное что в
panda was
панде было ещ
that the rulers could take people’s lives
что правители могли людей лишать жизни
at their behest, so in Russia Of course, this is
по своему велению так в России Конечно
not the case in Russia, there are
такого нет в России всё-таки есть там
still some other things, say, a judicial system, and
ещё какие-то скажем судебная системы и
so on Dasha, but in all other respects, the
так Даше но во всём остальном реально
Shapa panda really overlaps with
шапинская панде накладывается на
modern Russia  Ugh, well, you see, I
современную России Фу ну понимаете Я
want you in the Code of Criminal Procedure at one point, you
хочу вас УПК в одно в одном моменте вы
as a philosopher should know that the principle
как философ должны знать что принципе
of dialogue is
диалога
more accurate than the formulation, that jumping with
точнее формулировки что перепрыгнуть с
unprepared people from the general to the
неподготовленными человеком от общего к
specific. This is not entirely correct. Let’s
частному Это не совсем корректно Давайте
either talk about the general about Shang as a world
либо про общее про шанга как мирового
philosopher, or about the specific about Putin.
философа либо про частное про Путина То
Do you prefer the general or the
есть вы что предпочитаете общее или
particular, look, you can’t separate the general
частно смотрите нельзя разрывать общее
from the particular, you can’t Look, look again, look
от частного нельзя Смотри смотрите ещё
again, look, if we take the
раз ещё раз смотрите вот если мы возьмём
mathematical principle of differentiation
математический принцип дифференцирования
and integration, so differentiation is
и интегрирования так дифференцирование -
breaking it down into small parts, it’s
это разбивание на маленький рование это
putting it together, so like this, and here there
собирание воедино так вот так и тут не
is no differentiation without
существует дифференцирование без
integration and integration without
интегрирования и интегрирования без
differentiation, and here there is no
дифференцирования так и тут не
particular without the general and general
существует частного без общего и общего
without the particular, they are interconnected if we
без частного они взаимосвязаны если мы
consider the particular in isolation from the
будем рассматривать частное в отрыве от
general, it will not show the full essence of its
общего оно не покажет всего сути своего
philosophical significance if we
философского значения если мы будем
consider the general without going into
рассматривать общее но не вдаваясь в
the particular. This is how we will consider
частное Так мы будем рассматривать
only an abstract
только абстрактную
abstractionist Model of this world of
абстракционист скую Модель этого мира
this philosophical object of a philosophical
этого объекта философского философской
category, therefore we must always be
категории поэтому мы должны всегда вот
taught. Here is the first year of the
нас учили Вот первый курс да
Faculty of Philosophy, they always teach
философского факультета всегда учат
never single out individual parts of
никогда не выделяйте отдельные части
an object, but consider them as a
объекта А рассматривайте их в комплексе
whole, you cannot separate the particular from the
в целом нельзя отделять частное от
general and the general particular, they are inextricably
общего и общего частного они неразрывно
this is the dialectic
в том и есть э диалектика
of a single whole, it is both private and general
ээ единого целого оно и частное И общее
overnight.
в одночасье
I’m not talking
Я же говорю не
about study models, I’m talking about
про модели изучения я говорю про модели
conversation models, that is, they should be
беседы то есть они должны быть более
smoother because one can drive at a
плавные потому что один может ехать со
speed of
скоростью
150 Looking at his girlfriend and the other
150 Глядя на свою девушку а другой
something  -like at a speed of 60 that’s why
кое-как е со скоростью 60 вот я поэтому
I’m talking about this, I understand well, yes, that is,
я про это говорю хоро понял да то есть у
I understand from you, that is, let’s say your brain doesn’t
вас я понял то есть скажем ваш мозг не
have time to comprehend such philosophical
успевает познавать такие философские
Katya in such a fast pace of time, my
Кате в такой быстроте вниц времени мой
brain doesn’t have time, it has learned everything, but it doesn’t
мозг не успевает он всё познал но он не
have time like that  I need to answer quickly,
успевает так быстро отвечать мне надо
somehow more chopped up questions, that is,
как-то более рубленые вопросы то есть ес
if we switch to, for example, the
если мы переведём на например
technogenic principle, yes, you have a weak
техногенный принцип да у вас слабый
processor, if we switch to the
процессор если мы перейдём на
technogenic principle, my processor
техногенный принцип у меня процессор
is fine, but the wrong
нормально но подали не то подали не то
voltage was applied, the wrong voltage was applied, and
напряжение не то напряжение у вас да и
overheated yes
перегрелся да
no Okay Let's try to come from the
нет Ладно Давайте попробуем зайти с
other side That is, if from your
другого стороны То есть если с вашей
point of view from the point of view of Shango that you
точки с точки зрения шанго который вы
support Russia is like you Pangea
поддерживаете Россия - это как вы пангея
said yes to panda to panda
сказали да панде панде
and Great Britain is Atlantis Atlantis
а Великобритания это Атлантида Атлантида
That is, as if, well, I don’t agree with this
То есть как бы ну я с этим с этим не
well because because if you
согласен ну потому что потому что если
put it all together Well approximately That's what it
сложить Всё вместе Ну примерно То на то
turns out then look in Russia the
и выходит то смотрите в России реально
standard of living is actually much lower than in the
уровень жизни намного меньше чем в
UK the level of wages is
Великобритании уровень заработной платы
much lower by an order of magnitude people in
намного меньше на порядок люди в
poverty even in Arkhangelsk in Murmansk
бедности даже в Архангельске в Мурманске
still live in barracks for example
до сих пор в бараках живут например
are you in Russia when were you
есть вы в России когда были последний
last in 2005 in 2005 you should
раз в 2005 году в 2005 году вот вам бы
go again I’ve seen enough of chat roulette
ещё бы разок съездить Я в чат рулетки
I have enough Well chat roulette
насмотрелся Мне хватает Ну чат рулетки
there are not intellectuals who come no no I
там же не интеллектуалы приходят не не я
look at how people live like well if the
смотрю как живут люди типа ну если
cities there are often drunk  come there
города там часто выпившие приходят там
often not adequate not Well, look what
часто не адекват не Ну смотри какая
Let's So what I look I come in What is the
Давайте Так какая я смотрю захожу Какая
average salary in the UK and
средняя зарплата в Великобритании и
What is the average salary in Russia I have
Какая средняя зарплата в России Мне
enough to understand everything, well, What is the average
хватает всё понять ну и Какая средняя
salary in the UK Great Britain is
зарплата Великобритании Великобритании
eight times more than in Russia I compare
раз в восем больше чем в России я срав
How much they have  times more I looked Yes
Сколько у них во раз больше я смотрел Да
How much will it be in dollars
Сколько сколько это будет в долларах
Okay let's look uh in
Хорошо давайте так смотрите ээ в
UK dollars the average salary is
долларах Великобритании средняя зарплата
4,000 dollars how much in
4.000 долларов сколько в
Russia well in Russia I think 400 dollars
России ну в России я думаю 400 долларов
Yes no dollars 600-800 Duma that's
Да нет долларов 600-800 Дума вот в
eight times I said eight times  five
восемь раз я же сказал восемь раз в пять
is not 6 by 5 it will be 30 well 5 navo Well
не 6 на 5 это будет 30 ну 5 наво Ну
let it be in five Okay let's Let it be five for
пусть будет в пять Хорошо давайте Пусть
you Let it be five times easier
вам в пять Пусть легче будет в пять раз
let it be six five times yes Well,
пусть будет в шесть пять раз да Ну вот
but if we
но если мы
calculate the fees for education,
посчитаем плату за образование
medicine, communal apartments, then this is the value of this
медицину коммуналку то это значение эта
the difference is significantly reduced,
разница значительно понижается что
look, I see If we look in
смотрите я смотрю Если мы смотрим в
Russia, life expectancy is less
России продолжительность жизни меньше
than in the States and than in Britain, which means the
чем в Штатах и чем в Британии значит
level of medicine is
уровень медицины
worse, life expectancy, you
хуже продолжительность жизни это
understand, then from medicine and from money, that’s
понимаете то от медицины и от денег это
all, and from medicine, that’s
и только и от медицины это Это ж всё и
all  in the aggregate no no no no
есть всё в совокупности нет нет нет нет
no this is, uh, by the way, the
нет это Ээ как бы кстати говоря самый
richest countries have the highest status in terms of suicides.
высокий статус по самоубийствам у самых
That is, it’s not just
богатых стран То есть это не только
money, that is, longevity
деньги то есть как бы долгожительство
is far from just money, and vice versa, I
это далеко не только деньги и наоборот я
don’t know. Well, look what they have about
не знаю Ну смотри что там у них по
suicides  but if we look Yes, the
самоубийства но если мы смотрим Да
average standard of living Yes in the USA and
средний уровень жизни Да в США и в
Britain it is longer than in Russia
Британии он дольше чем в России
Okay Okay, I’ll try to come from the other
Ладно Хорошо попробую зайти с другого
side What country were you last in
Бока В какой стране последний раз вы
and when? Well, a year
были и когда Ну год
ago
назад
Czechoslovakia My last country is
Чехословакия Моя последняя страна
Thailand, I saw a bunch of English people there, they are
Таиланд я там видел кучу англичан они
people
люди
really That is, how would they be
действительно То есть как бы они по
all over the world, that is, how would I communicate with them,
всему миру то есть как бы я с ними
that is,
общался то есть
you know, I’m
знаете я приво
good with their passport, they let you in everywhere Well,
хороши с их паспортом пускат везде Ну
better than with ours, yes And in terms of money, in terms of
лучше чем с нашим это да А по деньгам по
morals, in behavior Well, damn, I don’t even
нравам по поведению Ну блин я даже не
know who’s better  Honestly, because
знаю кто лучше Честно говоря потому что
I’ll tell you, So there’s a crawfish of
я вам я вам скажу Так что там рачья
Bukharikov. Well, there’s definitely no less than ours,
бухариков Ну точно не меньше нашего есть
but there, for the same Bukharik, he lives
бы да там по тот же бухарик он живёт
better than Bukharik in Russia for some reason,
лучше чем бухарик в России почему-то
but he also lives 45 years, no
н тоже жит лет 45 не
longer on average,
дольше в среднем
we look at the statistics  Yes, and in
вре мы смотрим статистику Да и в
Britain they live longer,
Британии живут дольше
why Well, I don’t know Well, maybe they’re
почему Ну ну не знаю Ну может быть они
smarter
умнее
Pony maybe they’re worse look and since you
Поня может быть дурнее смотри а раз Вы
Thailand said of the Eastern philosophers
Таиланд сказали из восточных философов
who were you
кем вы
interested in, well, not philosophers, but
интересовались ну не философов а
Specifically I’ve been in recent
Конкретно Я вот сейчас последние
years I like Philosophy, well boom, who is the
годы Мне нравится фило ну буму кто
founder of Buddhism
основатель буддизма
boom, what a prince What was his name? Yes, I don’t
буму принц какой Как его звали Да я не
remember what his name was. I remember when they
помню как его звали Я помню когда его
started calling him bu bu, but what about this prince,
стали звать бу бу а как вот этот принц
prince irha?
прин ирха
Yes, the principle of Buddhism is
Да принцип буддизма
what to save a person not with fairy tales,
какой избавить человека не сказками а
namely, not in the afterlife, here and
то есть не в загробной жизни Здесь и
now, to save from suffering
сейчас избавить от страданий Каким
How to get rid of suffering Well,
образом надо избавиться от страданий Ну
there’s a long treatise, you think, I
там длинный трактат вы думаете Я всё
remember everything or something Well,
помню что ли Ну что
remember Well, I remember Now I’ll
помни Ну я помню помню Сейчас скажу
definitely say to treat both
точно относиться равно холодно и к
defeats, losses and the pleasures of
поражениям потерям и к удовольствиям
gain equally coldly.
приобретения то Это
600 dollars in Russia and also calmly And
600 долларов в России и также спокойно А
I understand that Russia is a country of Buddhists Yes,
понял то Россия страна буддистов Да им
they live there No no no not Russia I am Russia is an
они живут Нет нет нет не Россия я Россия
Orthodox country I understand Muslim it is
страна православная понял мусульманская
not necessary No well, in part Yes of course
не надо Не ну от части Да конечно
Muslim look but no no no we
мусульманская смотри а не не не у нас
also have Buddhists Kalmyks Kalmyks I know
тоже буддисты есть калмыки калмыки знаю
Buryats they are Buddhist Russia is a Muslim
буряты они буддист Россия мусульманская
non-Orthodox
не православная
country, we are pagans That is, it’s like
страна у нас язычники То есть как бы
if for example, look, you
есть если например смотрите вот у вас
have cities in which there is a mosque but no
есть города в которых есть мечеть но нет
church, for example
церкви например
Grozny, so what? That is, there are
Грозный так Ну и что во То есть там есть
Muslims there but there are no Christians, but on the contrary
мусульмане но нет христиан а наоборот
there are no  in any city you have Muslims
нету в любом городе есть мусульмане у
Well, firstly, Grozny grew up as a
вас Ну во-первых в Грозно рос
Muslim country No no no,
мусульманская страна Нет не нет
firstly there are churches in Grozny too,
во-первых в Грозном церкви тоже есть
okay that’s the question now Look, here’s the
ладно это раз теперь вопрос Смотри вот
main question of philosophy, you know
основной вопрос философии знаете
what, well, maybe I know Well, it’s
какой ну может быть знаю Ну он
formulated as whose
формулируется так чей
Crimea is yours  fiction and not philosophy And
Крым это ваша выдумка а не философия А
before that, it wasn’t my invention, it was that I
до этого всё не моя выдумка была что я
sold you about Schopenhauer And so on
вам впарил про шопенгауэра И так дальше
No, there were specific names, I was stupid In short, I just
Не ну там были конкретные фамилии я тупо
came up with all some
Короче придумывал просто всё какие-то
scientific works You, yes, I read just
научные труды Вы да да я читал вобще
stupidly In short, I’m not a
тупо Короче я никакой философский
faculty of philosophy  I was finishing I was
факультет заканчивал
finishing I wasn’t finishing I’m just
заканчиваю не заканчивали Я просто
short with you as short as possible
короче л с тебя короче как только можно
you read there pon
ты да там читал там пон
there whose Crimea I started with this same thing that I’m
там чей Крым я с этого же и начал что я
not a philosopher whose
не философ чей
Crimea I won’t answer this question
Крым я не буду отвечать на этот вопрос
because she’s too Glu
потому что она слишком Глу
stupid too stupid  this one is even more so
глупый слишком глупый этот тем более
for Damn, I'm almost dying you write there in the chat
для Блин я чуть не угораю вы там в чате
Andrey really knows so much
Андрей столько всего реально знает
Andrey knows so much damn it
Андрей столько знает блин
Oh I'm on the go here you're thinking some
О я тут на ходу вы думаю какие-то
treatises In short Shang I've
трактаты Короче шанга я никогда в жизни
never read that Schopenhauer in my life Are you in
не читал того шопенгауэра Вы что
short and what Yes  yes And I read this yes yes
Короче а что Да да А я читал это да да
letter on my Telegram directly at once axis VN and so much
пись на мий Telegram прям зараз ось ВН а
more and more respectfully YouTube taking
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the skarg ODS in your ban and even
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
more videos I don’t show people at the moment I don’t
багато видео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for
показуе информация про стримы тому для
you we are Mali operational  The link is written
тоб мы Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
directly at once and OK there in telegram okrim
прямо зараз а ОК там в телеграми окрим
video schetezh tsikava and korisna information
видео ще теж цикава и корисна информация
and we are sorry for you trimati postiyny
и мы повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
subscribe and
подпишись а